Guide to the La Farge Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS OF JOHN LA FARGE, 1893-1911; Series IV; 0.25; (1 box)
  - "Allegories - Part Two. One Hundred Masterpieces of Painting" ( McClure's Magazine, vol. 24), 1905 February (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Lecture on the art of painting, delivered in Boston; electrostatic typed copy, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Lecture on the "minor arts," delivered in Boston; electrostatic typed copy, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Recollections by JLF concerning The Earl and the Doctor, a journal of a Pacific voyage, 1906 October 11 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Copy of verses...written by me at some oblivious moment," typewritten with comments, 1907 March 25 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "The Teaching of Art," Scribner's Magazine, vol. 49, 1911 February (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Information on the contents of the Jaccaci Papers, Metropolitan Museum of Fine Arts, particularly in regard to Noteworthy Paintings in American Private Collections, edited by John La Farge and August Jaccaci, 1907, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
- WRITINGS ON JOHN LA FARGE, 1896-1972; Series V; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Series V contains articles, pamphlets and clippings on John La Farge and his work, In addition, there are several articles and clippings on other members of the La Farge family and on other subjects.
  The material has been arranged as follows: (a) studies of John La Farge; (b) publications on churches containing works by John La Farge; (c) clippings on John La Farge; (d) printed matter on other subjects.
  - Studies of JLF
    - Allen, Josephine L. "Exhibition of the Work of John La Farge," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1936 April (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Browne, Edythe Helen. "Wizard of the Window," Columbia, 1935 March (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bullard, E. John. "John La Farge at Tautira, Tahiti," TLS 1968 Sep 23
      See: box 6, folder 37
    - Cary, Elizabeth Luther. "THE MUSE OF PAINTING by John La Farge," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1909 December (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Cary Elizabeth Luther. Quotations from an article on JLF by Miss Cary published in the International Studio, 1909 October (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "John La Farge: A Reminiscent Note," N.Y. Times, 1936 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Cox, Kenyon. "Two Specimens of La Farge's Art in Glass," Burlington Magazine, vol. 13, 1908 June (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Downs, Joseph. "Stained Glass by John La Farge," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1945 May (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - File, Sister M. Jeanne, O.S.F. "An Evaluation of the Aesthetic Principles of John La Farge as Expressed in His Work in Glass," (dissertation, Catholic University of America), 1945 August (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Focillon, Henri. "John La Farge," The American Magazine of Art, 1936 May (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - La Farge, Henry. "John La Farge and the South Sea Idyll," reprinted from the Journal of the Warburg and Courtauld Institutes, vol. 7, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - La Farge, Henry. "John La Farge: a Reappraisal," proof for Art News, (1966 May?) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - La Farge, Mabel. "John La Farge: The Artist," The Commonweal, 1935 May 3 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Lansing, Josephine M. "A Self-Portrait by John La Farge," Bulletin of the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1935 February (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mather, Frank Jewett, Jr. "John La Farge -An Appreciation," The World's Work, 1911 March (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Murakata, Akiko. "John La Farge and Japan"
    - Roseboro, Viola. "John La Farge's Conversation," (typed ms.), Circa 1935 September (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Slottman, William. "Artist from Arcady," The Fordham Monthly, 1948 December (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Waern, Cecilia. "John La Farge, Artist and Writer," The Portfolio, no. 26, 1896 April (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - West, Richard V. "The Walker Art Building Murals," Occasional Papers I, Bowdoin College Museum of Art, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "John La Farge - Painter. 1835-1910," The Index of Twentieth Century Artists. Introduction by Bancel La Farge, 1936 February (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Publications on Churches Containing Works by JLF
    - Kelly, S.J. History of St. Paul's Protestant Episcopal Church in the City of East Cleveland (Adams Memorial Window by JLF), 1945 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Richardson, Henry Hobson. "A Description of Trinity Church by the Architect", undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Guide Book to Trinity Church in the City of Boston" (interior decoration by JLF), 1924 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Fragment from an article on Trinity Church, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Mount Vernon Congregational Church, Beacon St. & Mass. Ave., Boston" (memorial windows) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "In Memoriam. Grace Stanley Parker." (book-plate design based on Parker memorial window by JLF, St. Paul's Church, Stockbridge, Mass), undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Christ Church Parish, Springfield, Mass., 1817-1927" (memorial windows by JLF) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "Symbolism in Christ Church Cathedral, Springfield, Mass.", 1939 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Sunday bulletin of the Church of the Ascension, 5th Ave. at 10th St. (painting and windows by JLF), 1958 August 24 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Descriptive Pamphlet. Church of the Incarnation, Madison Ave. & 35th St., N.Y." (paintings and windows by JLF), undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Clippings on JLF
    - 1875, 1877-1881, 1906-1910 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Obituaries and tributes, 1910 November (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - 1910-1911 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - JLF Exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1936 March-June (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Newport and Boston Museum of Fine Arts exhibitions, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - 1936-1940, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Printed Matter on Other Subjects
    - Articles on art (Box 9, Folder 32)
      General note
      Transferred to MS 442, George Dudley Seymour Papers
      - Apollinaire, Guillaume. "Henri Matisse," La Phalange, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Saint-Gaudens, Homer, ed. "The Early Recognition of Augustus Saint-Gaudens," The Century Magazine, LXXVII (includes reminiscences of JLF), (c. 1908-1909) (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Cox, Kenyon. "Artist and Public," Scribner's Magazine, LV, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - La Farge, C. Grant. "The Cathedral of St. John the Divine," Scribner's Magazine, vol. XLI, no. 4, 1907 April (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - La Farge, C. Grant. "Peter's 'Old Country'," Scribner's Magazine, vol. LI, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - "The Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine," The American Architect (re: C. Grant La Farge), 1911 April 19 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Clippings on C. Grant La Farge and Bancel La Farge, 1911-1915 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Pamphlet: "Fort Nathan Hale Park. Hearing Before the Committee on Military Affairs, House of Representatives," statements of Wm. Howard Taft, George Dudley Seymour, and others, 1922 Jan 19
- FINANCIAL RECORDS AND MISCELLANY, 1879-1918; Series VI; 0.5; (1 box)
  "Financial records and miscellany" contain account books of John La Farge, a copy of the will of John La Farge and other papers related to his financial status, R.O.T.C. lessons of Bancel La Farge, and miscellaneous items. The arrangement is chronological.
  - Legal judgments involving John and Bancel La Farge: list and letter fragment, 1879-1896, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cash account book of John La Farge, 1895-1898 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
  - Copies of two poems in French by Gerard de Nerval, written on the back of pages from a catalogue of an art sale, 1903 February (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - List of expenses (JLF?)/Receipts of Henry Adams, n.y. November 1907 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Will of John La Farge (typed copy), 1910 April 23 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Notebook of Bancel La Farge for Yale ROTC instruction in mapping, Circa 1918 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lecture outline on "Drawing" by Bancel La Farge, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bookplate design by Bancel La Farge, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - List of Arabic words and their translations, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
- PHOTOS, 1850-1938, undated; Series VII; 0.5; (1 box)
  Transferred to MS 442, George Dudley Seymour Papers to papers of George Dudley Seymour
  Series VII, "Photos," has two subsections: (a) miscellaneous photographs and (b) photographs of John La Farge and his work.
  There are negatives and negative plates, as well as photographic prints. Very few of the items are dated; the arrangement is by type.
  - Photo of a portrait of John Frederic La Farge, father of JLF, 1850? (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Autographed photo of Julien Lemordant, 1919 June 18 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Photo of a miniature of Mary Juliana Seymour by John Trumbull, painted in 1792, with a description (from George Dudley Seymour), 1938 Feb 14
  - Stereoscopic Pictures of John Hay, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Photos of John La Farge, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Portrait plate of John La Farge and his personal seal, which frequently appears as an identifying stamp on his works (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Engraved plates of paintings by JLF: proofs of illustrations for Letters from Japan, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Three negative plates
    - Nos. 1 and 2 were taken in studio of John La Farge (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - No. 3 is a painting by JLF, "Ascension," altarpiece of the Church of the Ascension, New York City (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Three negative plates, taken in studio of JLF: photos of models posing for drapery studies (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Four negative plates
    - No. 1 is a cartoon of draped figure for unknown work (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Nos. 2, 3, and 4 are photos of model posing for above. There are also two negatives and two prints of the same cartoon and model. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Seven negatives of paintings by JLF (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Negatives and prints of THE ANNUNCIATION, THE ADORATION OF THE MAGI, and of a (press?) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of John La Farge paintings in the Memorial Exhibition, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (includes works by other artists), 1911 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of John La Farge paintings in the Memorial Exhibition..., 1911 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Photos of oil paintings and mural decorations by JLF
    - PORTRAIT OF A BOY (2) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - ON THE BAYOU TECHE (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - EVENING SKY, NEWPORT (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - FLOWERS IN A BOWL, BEFORE WINDOW (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - FRUIT (panel) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - FRUIT (BRANCH OF ORANGES?) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - THE GOLDEN AGE (also called EVE) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - HALT OF THE WISE MEN (2) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - EROS (also called SPIRIT OF WOODLAND) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - THE NATIVITY (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - LA SUONATORE (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - MADONNA AND CHILD (altarpiece, Portland, Me., Cathedral) (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Photos of oil paintings and mural decorations by JLF, title or authenticity uncertain: (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Little seated figure, jar of flowers on either side (2) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - A CANDLEMAS PROCESSION IN A MONASTERY (or THE OFFICE OF MATINS) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - ROMANTIC LANDSCAPE (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - CHRIST, TIME, AND THE MOURNER (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - THE SOURCE (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Watercolors by JLF, photos of
    - THE FISHERMAN AND THE DJINN (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - MOTHER AND CHILD (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - ISAIAH (study for figure in Trinity Church, Boston) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - DESIGN FOR A STAINED GLASS WINDOW (Holmes Memorial) (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Watercolors by JLF (Japan), photos of (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - TOKIO GEISHA (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - GINRIKISHA BOY (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - KWANNON (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Watercolors by JLF (Samoa and Tahiti), photos of (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - SEATED SIVA DANCE AT NIGHT, SAMOA (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - SPEARING FISH, SAMOA (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - AFTERGLOW, TAUTIRA RIVER, TAHITI (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - TAUTIRA RIVER, TAHITI (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Photo of the actual Tautira River (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Photos of MAUA: OUR BOATMAN by JLF (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Glass and mural designs by JLF, photos of, designs for
    - Chapel Window, St. John's Cathedral (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - MADONNA (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - ANTIQUE ACTOR IN RED CLOAK LOOKING AT HIS MASK (Booth Memorial) (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - CHRIST LEADING THE SOUL (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Unidentified (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Stained glass windows by JLF
    - Eight negatives and seven prints of THE RESURRECTION, Congregational Church, Methuen, Mass.; + photos of interior and exterior of the church (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Photos of Ames Memorial Window, Unitarian Church, North Easton, Mass. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Stone Memorial Window, the Old Stone Church, Cleveland, Ohio (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Photo of the Adams Memorial Window, St. Paul's P.E. Church, E. Cleveland, Ohio (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Ten negatives (includes 5 windows in Trinity Church, Buffalo, N.Y.; PEONIES BLOWN IN WIND; LUNETTE; DECORATIVE PANEL; PEACOCKS AND PEONIES) (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Photos of the Watson Memorial Window, Trinity Church, Buffalo, N.Y. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Photo of PEONIES BLOWN IN WIND (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Two negatives (possibly of SAINT PAUL, Judson Memorial Church, New York, N.Y.) (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Drawings by JLF: 15 negatives and 16 prints
  - Sepia drawings by JLF, photos of
    - THE NATIVITY (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - THE ADORATION OF THE MAGI (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - THE ASCENSION (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Photo of engraving (cliche verre); photo of PORTRAIT, HEAD OF A YOUTH (drawing inscribed "Frank LF, 1857-1858"); and MIDSUMMER EVE (illustration for book or magazine) (Box 11, Folder 32)
- CATALOGUES, 1878-1968; Series VIII; 1.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series has two subsections: (a) catalogues of John La Farge sales and exhibitions and (b) catalogue of the works of John La Farge by Henry Adams La Farge.
  The first subsection contains catalogues of sales of La Farge art works and books, as well as catalogues of La Farge works exhibited during his lifetime and after his death in 1910.
  The second part of the series consists of materials related to the catalogue of the works of John La Farge, compiled by Henry Adams La Farge. Included are Henry La Farge's notes, preliminary catalogue entries, and the final catalogue itself. The latter consists of a loose-leaf notebook on oil paintings and mural decorations and a card file for watercolors, stained glass, and drawings. Though some entries in the catalogue are quite brief, many contain most if not all of the following information: title, owner and/or gallery, measurements, description (some with accompanying photo), locations of photographs and exhibitions, and bibliographical references. The card file forms a separate box and is provided with subject headings designated by Henry La Farge.
  - John La Farge Exhibitions and Sales
    - Catalogue of the paintings of John La Farge to be sold at auction, Messrs. Peirce & Co., Boston, 1878 November 19-20 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Catalogue of the John La Farge collection of oil and watercolors sold at Assignee's Sale by Ortgies & Co., 1884 April 17 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Catalogue of the works by JLF exhibited at Durand - Ruel Galleries, N.Y.C. (7 copies), 1895 February 25 - March 5 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Catalogues of works by JLF, Montrose Gallery, N.Y.C., 1901 January 24 - February 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Programs and invitation to private showings of JLF paintings commissioned for the Supreme Court Room of the Capitol, St. Paul, Minnesota, 1904, 1905 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Catalogue of a portion of the library of JLF, Anderson Auction Co., to be sold, 1909 March 24-25 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Catalogue of the private library of the late JLF, Merwin-Clayton Sales Co., to be sold, 1911 February 20, 21, 23 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Catalogue of the sale of the JLF Collection, American Art Galleries, N.Y.C., 1911 March (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Catalogue: "Loan Exhibition of Paintings by JLF and His Descendents," Wildenstein & Co., N.Y.C. (2 copies), 1931 March (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Catalogue of JLF Exhibition, Metropolitan Museum of Art, and a printed invitation, 1936 March 23 - April 2[illegible] (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Catalogue of exhibition, "Small Pictures by Famous Painters," Walker Galleries, N.Y.C., 1937 October 11-30 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Catalogue of JLF loan exhibition at the Macbeth Gallery, N.Y.C., 1948 April 26 - May 1. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Exhibition handlist: "150 Years of American Drawing, 1780-1930, from the Collection of John Davis Hatch," Williams College Museum of Art, 1965 October 25 - November 1. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Catalogue of the JLF exhibition at the Graham Gallery, N.Y.C., 1966 May 4 - June 10 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Catalogue of exhibition: "JLF. Oils and Watercolors," Kennedy Galleries, N.Y.C., 1968 January 24 - February 1[illegible] (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Catalogue of exhibition: "American Still Life Painting, 1860-1900," Adelson Galleries, Boston, Mass., 1968 November 4-30 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "JLF. Drawings and Watercolors," Museum News, Toledo Museum of Art (catalogue of the Museum's exhibition), 1968 Winter (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Catalogue of the Works of John La Farge by Henry La Farge
    - Notes representing HLF's efforts to compile catalogue information: titles of existing works by JLF, descriptions, provenance, present owners (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Notes... (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
    - Title cards (72 3" x 5" carbon copies) of works by JLF, brief identifications (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Notes on JLF works mentioned in exhibition and sale catalogues, 1876-1923 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Preliminary catalogue entries on notebook paper:
      - Watercolors, glass, drawings (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - Watercolors, drawings, oils, arranged by gallery or exhibition (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Watercolors (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Watercolors (in loose-leaf notebook) (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Glass, drawings, and engravings (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Catalogue of the works of JLF (typed, with additions and corrections, in loose-leaf notebook): OIL PAINTING and MURAL DECORATIONS (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Catalogue of the works of JLF (4" x 6" cards, typed): WATERCOLORS, STAINED GLASS, SCULPTURE, DRAWINGS (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Watercolors (white cards)
        - 1. Early works, book illustrations, mural sketches (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 2. Early landscapes (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 3. Flower studies (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 4. Glass designs, allegories, (undated) (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 5. Japan, 1886 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 6. Hawaii, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 7. Samoa, 1890-1891 (not including dancers) (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 8. Tahiti, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 9. Fiji, Java, Ceylon, Red Sea, etc., 1891 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 10. Glass and mural designs from 1875; undated sketches through, 1887 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 11. Glass and mural designs from, 1887 (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Stained Glass (orange cards) (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Sculpture (Box 15, Folder 29)
      - Drawings (blue cards)
        - 1. Through, 1859 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 2. 1860-1869 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 3. Circa, 1870-1879 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 4. 1880-1889, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 5. Japan and South Seas (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 6. Undated studies, Circa 1890-1910 (Box 15, Folder 29)
        - 7. Engravings from designs by JLF (Box 15, Folder 29)
- MICROFILM INDEX, SERIES I-VIII
  La Farge family papers, including correspondence, writings, financial records and other papers of John La Farge (1835-1910), Bancel La Farge (1865-1938), and Henry Adams La Farge (1902-), primarily relating to John La Farge and his work as a painter and artist.
  HM 48 consists of six reels (duplicates Series I-VIII). Filmed 1973 Feb.
  - Box 1, Folder 1- 34 (Reel 1)
  - Box 1 - 3, Folder 35 - 66 (Reel 2)
  - Box 4 - 5, Folder 1- 29 (Reel 3)
  - Box 5 - 9, Folder 30 - 36 (Reel 4)
  - Box 10 - 13, Folder 1 - 22 (Reel 5)
  - Box 13 - 15, Folder 23 - 29 (Reel 6)
- Additional Material, 1936-(1943-1949)-1962; Accession 1980-M-007; 2.5 linear feet (3 boxes, 1 folio box)
  - Personal correspondence, 1939, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Supreme Headquarters, Allied Expeditionary Force (S.H.A.E.F.), Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives (M.F.A.A.) office files
    - Correspondence on return of works of art to owner nations, 1942-1948, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - M.F.A.A., Second Army
      - Correspondence re: administrative headquarters, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
      - Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - First Canadian Army, [Belgium and] Holland
      - Reports on archival repositories and monuments, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Reports on German thefts of works of art, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Maps, lists, and civil affairs handbooks
      - Northern/Southern Bavaria, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Belgium, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - France, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - France, 1944, undated (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
      - Germany, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      - Germany: correspondence re: removal of German works of art to U.S.; specialist M.F.A.A. opposition; controversy re: Crown of St. Stephen, 1943-1949, 1953-1954, undated (Box 2, Folder 16-19)
      - Netherlands, 1944-1945, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Council for Historic Sites and Buildings [and correspondence on return of works of art to owner nations], 1948-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Review of John D. Skilton, Jr., Défense de l'Art Européen: typescript, with letter about Skilton, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Printed matter, 1936, 1945-1949, 1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - Works of Art in (Italy, Germany, Greece): Losses and Survivals in the War, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Thomas P. Hazard, Civil Affairs: An Experiment in Reconstruction (mimeograph, inscribed), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Oversize (Folio)
    - Printed matter, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Maps: northwest Europe; Holland/Belgium/France; England, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Additional Material, 1990; Accession 1991-M-052; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1991 Feb
  Received from: James L. Yarnall, 1991 Jan 17
  - John La Farge: Watercolors and Drawings; catalog published by the Hudson River Museum of Westchester, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from John La Farge to Edward H. Childs, his son-in-law, husband of Frances La Farge (originals and photocopies; transcriptions by James Yarnall with Mary La Farge), 1900-1903 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    Originally part of Accession 1992-M-031
    Received from: Mary A. La Farge, 1991 Nov 13
  - Letter from John La Farge to Louis Bancel Binsse (first cousin), 1905 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, undated; Accession 1994-M-071; 2 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1994 Mar
  Received from: Deposited on 1979 May 15; gift of Mary La Farge, 1994 Mar 4
  - Ten binders containing descriptions of art work: title, artist's name, dimensions, exhibition locations and dates, provenance, and bibliographical references, undated (Box 1–2)